You've had quite a lot
of administrative work to do today.
Ah, Grantz. I'll make some tea.
It would be my pleasure
to join you, Your Majesty.
Don't be so formal.
We're not king and prime minister here.
I just want to speak as friends right now.
Understood, Orphanse.
Are you troubled over
Princess Anisphia again?
I've never not been troubled over her!
She's two years older than your Euphyllia,
and yet that imbecile shows
no signs of settling down.
If she settled down, she wouldn't
be Princess Anisphia anymore.
Her magicology research is
showing results, is it not?
The problem is that she has too much talent
for causing trouble outside her research.
A parent's work is never done.
It seems that even my son has
become problematic of late.
You mean the matter with
Baron Cyan's daughter?
Yes. That fool Algard...
He has no sense of the standards
he should strive for as future king.
He certainly has been acting quite boldly.
I'm sorry, Grantz.
I know the royal family essentially
forced this engagement onto you.
It's Euphyllia's job to win
the heart of her betrothed.
It should prove to be good experience
for her as the future queen.
How philosophical of you.
But—
Father!
I pray the evening finds you well.
I, Anisphia...
have taken Lady Euphyllia away!
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
What is wrong with you?!
Please... let me explain my reasoning...
Reasoning?! What excuse is
there for abducting someone?!
I was out for a test flight
with my Witch's Broom,
and I kind of ended up crashing the
soirée at the nobles' academy...
And there's yet another
problem you've caused!
You fool of a daughter!
And then Al said he was breaking off
his engagement with Lady Euphyllia.
What?
He broke off the engagement.
Whose engagement... with whom?
Al and Lady Euphyllia.
It's true.
I am terribly sorry.
In the middle of a soirée...
in front of all those people...
Of all the times to...
Algard!
What in the world were you thinking?!
Lady Euphyllia...
I'm sorry, Grantz. It seems
my judgment was premature.
Not at all.
Euphyllia.
I had heard that you and the prince
had not grown any closer.
Yes.
It is unfortunate that it ended this way.
I am... very sorry.
No need to apologize.
What you need to think about now
is what you will do from here.
How shall I be punished?
What Euphyllia does from here, eh?
That's it, Father!
That's the great idea
I came to share with you!
Great idea, you say?
Father, Duke Grantz...
Please give Lady Euphyllia to me!
I'll do everything in my
power to make her happy!
W...
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
What kind of ridiculous
joke are you making?!
I'm being completely serious, Father.
That's even more frightening!
What, so either way would be wrong?
You're the one who's wrong!
What I'm saying is...
I want to welcome Lady
Euphyllia as my assistant!
Me... as your assistant?
S-So cute...
Those puppy-dog eyes must be
some sort of magic on their own!
Her entire existence is OP!
Th-The problem here is not that
the engagement was annulled,
but that he declared it publicly.
Correct?
Well, yes...
Since so many people heard it,
we can't take it back.
If you want to arrange an engagement for a
lady who's already been spurned by royalty,
your choice of potential partners is limited.
And as brilliant as Euphyllia is,
I can't just haphazardly hand
her off to some foreign nation.
After all, Lady Euphyllia...
is loved by the spirits!
They say she commands more magical
attributes than anyone in history.
And she excels in both etiquette
and the martial arts! She's a genius!
She's the Kingdom of Palettia's treasure!
The best of the best!
And above all...
She's beautiful and cute!
However, this matter has left a
stain on her life as a noble lady.
So when you say you want her as your
assistant, you mean in magicology?
The study of magical science that I advocate,
"magicology," will, in my opinion,
bring about a new of technology.
Well, yes...
It is certainly progressive
and full of unknown potential.
Exactly!
If shared with the public,
it could greatly impact the entire kingdom.
But you have refrained from
announcing it to the masses.
I don't really like taking center stage.
I just want to immerse
myself in my research.
I see. In other words,
you want your achievements
in magicology to be...
Precisely, Duke Grantz!
Why not have Lady Euphyllia announce
the results of our joint research
to restore her damaged reputation?
M-Me?!
It could, if nothing else,
give people something besides the
broken engagement to talk about.
Right?!
But... me as your assistant?
There's plenty that I stand
to gain from this deal, too.
Given the way I am,
my reputation is so bad that
I can't hire a skilled assistant.
But that's...
But you are incredibly talented,
and you'd be the perfect choice
to promote magicology to the masses.
But wouldn't I be taking
all the credit for your work?
Nah.
I'm just doing it out of love!
For magicology, you mean?
Yep!
It'll change the world we live in.
It's new technology, packed
with dreams and romanticism!
And if possible, I really want
you to fall in love, too.
Y-You're referring to magicology, right?!
Do you remember what you once said to me?
Oh, you mean what she said when
she renounced her right to the throne?
Father?
A long time ago, Princess Anisphia said...
Father!
Hmm? What is it?
I don't want to marry a man!
If I fall in love,
I want it to be with a woman!
Are you just making various excuses
when all you really want
is to make Euphyllia your own?
Th-That's not... totally wrong,
but... I mean...
I don't want to accidentally
get pregnant or anything...
What is wrong with you?!
How dare you speak of such an
important royal duty in that way?!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
You're gonna crush your
precious princess's head!
It would match your twisted
disposition perfectly!
What's the point in passing my genes
along when I can't even use magic?!
It's not about having any point!
Do you not understand a father's
desire to see his daughter's child?!
I feel so hopeless, I could cry!
Well, I'm already crying!
Bawling like a baby!
You haven't shed a single tear!
Can we just say I understand now?!
Is this how a parent and child should be?
Father?
I'm sorry, Euphyllia.
F-Father?
Grantz... bowed his head!
You have worked hard to avoid
shaming the Magenta household.
I believed that encouraging you to
that end was my job as your father.
Wh-What are you saying?
I now feel that I may have been mistaken.
I'm who I am today because of
the education you've given me!
This was all my own fault!
Because I am insufficient as a duke's
daughter, and as a future queen...
I'm a fool who has besmirched
the name of our—
No daughter of mine
is a fool.
You lived up to all my expectations.
Too well, in fact.
I've begun to question whether what
you wanted played any part in it.
Please stop.
I really haven't... I'm all right...
I'm sure I haven't been
a very good father...
or even a good person.
You don't need to worry about our family.
If there's something you want,
I'll make it happen, even if
it pits me against the king.
Euphyllia...
Would becoming queen be too much for you?
Was this really the right thing to do?
The princess's villa is an ideal
place for her to lay low.
And her proposal of joint magicology
research is worth considering.
Besides...
Besides?
Even if Euphyllia were to be plundered,
that might not be so bad.
Grantz!
I was joking.
But there may be meaning in giving
Euphyllia to Princess Anisphia.
What do you mean?
No law says that there is only one
path to succeeding the throne.
Should a prime minister
be saying that to a king?
I thought we were supposed to be
speaking as friends right now.
Princess Anisphia could be the
next ruler of this kingdom.
It's not such a bad dream to have, is it?
That's not a dream I ever want to have.
It's just a nightmare.
Are you curious about that?
It's a Thermal Pot,
made with a fire spirit stone!
Did you invent it?
It's set to maintain a given temperature,
so it can have tea ready in no time.
It can be used for bathwater, as well.
I can even wash dishes without
having the water go cold.
Please try some.
I see.
It is indeed delicious.
Thank you for saying so.
That's very convenient.
It seems as though it could
have many other uses, as well.
Right? You totally get it!
I guess those who get it... really get it.
Oh, hey! Since you're here,
come see my workshop!
Huh?
If you're gonna be my assistant,
you should get a feel for the place first!
But, Princess Anisphia...
You can call me "Anis."
Oh, and I'll call you "Euphie"!
We're not strangers anymore, after all!
Er... H-Huh?
There's no stopping Miss Anis at this point.
Just think of it as being bewitched
by a demon and give up.
Let's go, Euphie!
Anis, wai—
Hang on tight!
Welcome to my workshop!
There are so many things
I've never seen before...
You made all these, Princess Anisph—
I mean, Miss Anis?
That's right! Praise me, Euphie!
W-Well done.
Please don't spoil Miss Anis too much.
The tools themselves are remarkable,
but I'm shocked that you even had
the idea to use spirit stones.
Oh, well, it's spirits that make
the use of magic possible, right?
But I can't even sense spirits at all,
so I can't use magic.
I had no idea...
So I had to think of something
that could replace the spirits!
You truly are amazing, Miss Anis.
I've always taken the existence
of magic and spirits for granted.
I never even considered why
they work the way they do.
It's good that you never
had to think about it.
Since you're compatible with
so many different spirits,
you're OP enough to use
any attribute you want.
OP?
The truth is...
I actually envy people who can
use magic. Just a little bit.
Um...
Because as a princess who can't use magic,
Miss Anis is the very definition
of a useless royal.
Disrespect! Pure disrespect!
Off with your head!
How could you say such a thing?!
In the Kingdom of Palettia,
it is said that those who formed
contracts with greater spirits
were the primogenitors of the royal
and noble families, is it not?
Yeah, but... I know, but...
Which means the current royalty and nobility
are qualified to be as such
by the authority of magic.
Miss Anis, on the other hand...
Yeah, but...
Magic tools have even more
potential than magic itself!
You just don't get it at all, Ilia!
If something equivalent to magic could be
used to give the people more freedom...
We're not talking about something more
than magic. We're talking about magic.
But you use the Thermal Pot, too!
How would the very conservative nobles
feel about their loss of authority?
What's that supposed to mean?!
I won't let you use it anymore!
This young woman will prove to be a
powerful medicine for this kingdom.
Lady Euphyllia?
Um, it's nothing...
Well, it's late, so we're done for today,
but to celebrate your arrival here,
I'll make you a special magic tool!
For me?
Look forward to it!
Miss Anis, please stop!
This stuff's hard to take off
alone, isn't it? So I'll help!
Wait...
You can borrow some of my pajamas.
Thank you...
Now please go over there.
Come join me, my lady.
I was just kidding! I won't do anything!
Please excuse me.
Thanks for coming with me today.
I know a lot has happened,
but I hope you'll see the appeal
of magicology and myself soon.
Yes... You are just as crazy
as the rumors say...
And even more mysterious.
Just... what are you?
What... do you mean?
Just from what happened today, I can tell
that you are very clever,
and that you have big dreams.
I'm sure you're capable of living
more freely than anyone else.
So why did you help me?
Someone like me, who wasn't
even your friend...
I had lots of reasons.
Part of it was that I like you,
and part of it was self-interest.
But the biggest reason was
because you're perfect.
Um...
You've always been calm and
in control of your emotions.
Even after what happened at the soirée,
you still tried to remain
strong and righteous.
You really are the perfect duke's daughter.
I guess that's why I just
couldn't leave you alone.
I don't understand. You can't leave
me alone because I'm perfect?
If you're someone who can smile on
your own, you can do what you want.
But it didn't look like you were
able to do that as you are now.
If I really am as free as you say,
then I just can't help reaching out
to someone who lacks that freedom.
And that was your only reason for...
It may seem like a trivial thing,
but it's very important to me.
Magicians should use their
magic to make others smile.
You've worked so hard.
Just rest now, Euphie.
Goodnight.
Episode Two
Acquisition of an Assistant
for Both Profit and Pleasure
Episode Three
The Rainbow Magic Sword
of Longing and Reminiscence